# **TERRY MCKEE**

226 W Fairview Way, Palatine, IL (630) 788-1448 javalion@hotmail.com

# **Experienced Software Professional**

# **Executive Summary**

I have more than 17 years of experience designing, developing and tuning software for organizations in the financial, retail, pharmaceutical and mapping industries. Having worked on dozens of challenging projects, I have used a broad range of skills to solve a plethora of problems. I have a record of delivering innovative solutions and meeting aggressive deadlines.

# Skills

Java
 Javascript
 Hibernate

Oracle • JQuery • HTML

Amazon Web Services
 Spring
 Architecture

#### **Experience**

CME Group 2011 – present

# Lead Software Engineer, 2012 - present

Identified improvements for clearing application deployments

**Details:** Helped teams by evaluating performance of clearing applications for dozens of upgrades, functional changes and architectural redesigns. When I identified problems, I researched solutions and provided thorough recommendations on how to proceed.

Created technical training sessions for department

Details: Led training sessions on performance engineering, Java 8 topics and more at "Code Jam" sessions.

# Senior Software Engineer, 2011 - 2012

Evaluated performance of Electronic Trade Posters

**Details:** Worked with development and QA teams across the organization to measure the performance of the electronic trade posters. I also recommended solutions for application bottlenecks to improve throughput.

Navteq 2004 - 2011

# Senior Architect, 2008 - 2011

Led architecture effort for "Natural Guidance" and "Discover Cities" projects

**Details:** Designed database and class model, prototyped key system areas in Java and Oracle. Defined XML sample data and schema definitions (XSD). Communicated key design elements using written documents, group-collaboration and video recordings. Worked closely with business analyst to clarify stakeholders' functional and non-functional requirements.

# Built flexible prototypes using Spring

**Details:** Designed and implemented prototypes with clearly defined interfaces. Greatly simplified unit, functional and performance testing by making use of Spring Dependency Injection. Also using Spring DI, evaluated different algorithms to determine the advantages / disadvantages of any given solution.

#### Active leader driving rollout of agile across organization

**Details:** Initiated training of Mumbai staff by discussing the agile mindset that is essential in becoming successful in an agile adoption.

Created lightweight user story perspective model to aid individual scrum teams in generating new stories as well as evaluating the quality of identified stories.

#### Developed Quick-Edit Tool for easy maintenance of development data

**Details:** Built web-based tool that removed several time-consuming manual steps that were required for managing development data. Designed and developed system in under one month using JBoss, Hibernate, Servlets, JSPs, HTML and CSS.

#### Motivated over 150 colleagues in presentation – "The Essence of Agile Methodologies"

**Details:** Researched and presented the most important shared aspects of agile methodologies, including: self-organizing teams that meet and listen to each other regularly, continuous improvement and gaining early and regular feedback of software development from stakeholders.

# · Organized and led training to increase Java skills across department

**Details:** Created training material and discussion content for 10-week session on latest changes to Java versions 5 and 6. Identified specific locations within existing codebase where updated Java functionality was especially relevant.

# Project Lead, 2007 - 2008

Redesigned and developed Oracle PL/SQL analysis framework

**Details:** Created scalable highly optimized Oracle framework used with Struts based web-application. Enhanced application with custom caching and asynchronous results notification. Designed web page elements using HTML, JSP, Servlets, AJAX and CSS.

Managed user expectations by reviewing project priorities on weekly basis

**Details:** Led weekly meeting to inform stakeholders of defect resolution, discuss priorities for the next week and review long-term goals of tool.

# Senior Software Engineer, 2004 - 2007 (consultant at Solugenix 2004-2005)

Enhanced enterprise-level Java Swing application using standard design patterns

**Details:** Recommended and developed user-interface changes to directly improve usability of application. Implemented industry-accepted design patterns and frameworks such as Model-View-Controller (MVC), Observer pattern and Strategy pattern to build a system that is well-suited for easier expansion and maintenance for years to come.

Abbott Labs 2003 - 2004

Application Analyst, 2003 - 2004

- Supported J2EE software running on BEA Weblogic Application Server
- Developed and tuned Oracle components for contract management system

Spiegel Corp. 1999 - 2003

# Programmer Analyst, 1999-2003

- Corrected problems on the www.spiegel.com and www.eddiebauer.com websites
- Built custom CORBA Java client for Enterprise Warehouse System

# Certifications

- Sun Certified Web Component Developer
- Sun Certified Business Component Developer
- Sun Certified Java Developer
- Sun Certified Java Programmer
- Certified Scrum Master

# **Education**

**DePaul University** Chicago Graduated: 2014

Master of Science (MS) - Software Engineering: Software Architecture

Northern Illinois University DeKalb Graduation: 1999

Bachelor of Arts (BA) - Translation and Business Spanish